{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Octavia Spencer","incorrectAnswers":["Bérénice Bejo","Jessica Chastain","Melissa McCarthy"],"question":"Who won the 2011 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Minny Jackson in The Help?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"And you Brutus?","incorrectAnswers":["Are you a brute?","Why be brutal?","Live laugh love"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Et tu Brute?' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Five","incorrectAnswers":["Twelve","Two","Nine"],"question":"How Many Consecutive Wimbledon Titles Did Bjorn Borg Win?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sana'a","incorrectAnswers":["Chisinau","Tarawa","Suva"],"question":"What is the capital city of Yemen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"An Advent calendar","incorrectAnswers":["A Holy calendar","A Kwanzaa calendar","A Countdown calendar"],"question":"What kind of calendar used to count the days until Christmas and often has a treat behind each window?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Czech Republic","Canada","Scotland"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of The Blue Mountains?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Artichokes ","incorrectAnswers":["Spinach","Tomatoes","Onions"],"question":"Which vegetable comes in 'globe' and 'Jerusalem' varieties?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Christmas Carol'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sete","incorrectAnswers":["Sieben","Sept","Dois"],"question":"What is the Portuguese word for 'seven'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Singapore","Ukraine"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Three horizontal bands of red, yellow, and red with the national coat of arms towards the left.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neil Gaiman","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","H. P. Lovecraft","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Fragile Things'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Iron","incorrectAnswers":["Copper","Gold","Nickel"],"question":"What is the heaviest element that can be formed by regular fusion reactions in the core of a star?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Yasser Arafat","incorrectAnswers":["Yitzhak Rabin","Shimon Peres","Abu Qatada"],"question":"Which Palestinian leader received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1994?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Dead Zone'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anne Bancroft","incorrectAnswers":["Gloria Swanson","Shirley MacLaine","Glenn Close"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Mrs. Robinson in The Graduate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dustin Hoffman","incorrectAnswers":["Dan Aykroyd","Gérard Depardieu","Donald Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has had roles in films including Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events and Kramer vs. Kramer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"All right, Mr. DeMille, I'm ready for my close-up.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You shall not pass!\"","\"What’s the most you ever lost on a coin toss?\"","\"Get off my lawn.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Sunset Blvd.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Anna Pavlova ","incorrectAnswers":["Nikita Blini","Ilyana Tiramisu","Sasha Macaron"],"question":"Who was the female Russian dancer who had a dessert named after her?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Louis Bleriot","incorrectAnswers":["The Wright Brothers","Amelia Earhart","Glenn Curtiss"],"question":"Who was the first to fly over the English Channel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["Texas","New York","Florida"],"question":"Which U.S. state has the largest sub-national economy in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Billy Joel","incorrectAnswers":["George Michael","Stevie Wonder","Cyndi Lauper"],"question":"Who Had A 1984 Hit With The Song \"The Longest Time\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lignite","incorrectAnswers":["Metamorphous","Iodine","Quartz"],"question":"What is the lowest grade of coal called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Christopher Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","J. R. R. Tolkien","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The History of Middle-earth'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ben-Hur","incorrectAnswers":["Anatomy of a Murder","The Diary of Anne Frank","The Nun's Story"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A group of low-level criminals fight to track down a priceless stolen diamond.","incorrectAnswers":["A research team in Antarctica is hunted by a shape-shifting alien.","When two girls move to the country, they have adventures with the forest spirits who live nearby.","In order to power the city, beasts have to scare children so that they scream."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Snatch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Shirley Bassey","John Barry","Carly Simon"],"question":"Which musician performed the theme song for the James Bond film 'Die Another Day'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Roth","incorrectAnswers":["Paul Newman","Tobey Maguire","Elijah Wood"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including The Incredible Hulk and Pulp Fiction?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sochi","incorrectAnswers":["Moscow","Saint Petersburg","Kazan"],"question":"Which of these Russian cities is located on the Black Sea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Stuarts","incorrectAnswers":["The Tudors","The Plantagenets","The Lancasters"],"question":"Which Royal House Ruled England Between 1603 & 1714?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Narcissus","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Apollo","Perseus"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who was the beautiful young man Echo fell in love with?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kenneth Branagh","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Ironside","Luke Evans","Tom Waits"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets and Dunkirk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Clay","incorrectAnswers":["Wood","Metal","Glass"],"question":"In India's popular Tandoori chicken, the food is cooked in an oven made of which material?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gerard Butler","incorrectAnswers":["Hugh Jackman","Robert Redford","Jim Carrey"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including 300 and Watchmen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Poltergeist","incorrectAnswers":["The Exorcist","The Shining","Halloween"],"question":"Which classic scary movie features the line 'They're Here'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Janet Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Celine Dion","Kylie Minogue","Sinead O'Connor"],"question":"Who had her first UK top 10 hit with What Have You Done For Me Lately? in 1986 at the age of nineteen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cycling","incorrectAnswers":["Cricket","Gymnastics","Ice Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Lance Armstrong associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"KFC","incorrectAnswers":["McDonald's","Subway","Domino's"],"question":"Food from which fast food chain is traditionally eaten for Christmas dinner in Japan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Feudalism","incorrectAnswers":["Capitalism","Socialism","Communism"],"question":"The 15th century was characterized by a decline in which economic system?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Lesotho","Netherlands","Haiti"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.th' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'The Division Bell'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Turkic","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Sino-Tibetan","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'South Azerbaijani' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Supremes","incorrectAnswers":["Casting Crowns","The Vandellas","The Temptations"],"question":"Which Group Was Originally Called The Primettes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thalidomide","incorrectAnswers":["Bextra","Penicillin","Actos"],"question":"Which drug, later found to have devastating side effects, was launched in 1958 to help pregnant women overcome morning sickness?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Warsaw","incorrectAnswers":["Helsinki","Paris","Düsseldorf"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Poland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Fatigue","incorrectAnswers":["Weight loss","Headache","Nausea"],"question":"Which of the following is a symptom of hypothyroidism?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Great Gatsby","incorrectAnswers":["The Shining","The Silmarillion","American Psycho"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'In my younger and more vulnerable years my father gave me some advice that I’ve been turning over in my mind ever since.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Albatross","incorrectAnswers":["Emperor Penguin","Eurasian Coot","Mallard"],"question":"Which is the largest aquatic bird by wingspan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Libya","Morocco","Tunisia"],"question":"What African country has parts of both the Arabian and Libyan deserts?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Adam Mickiewicz","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","G. K. Chesterton","Marcel Proust"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Pan Tadeusz'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Malcolm","incorrectAnswers":["Lysander","Mercutio","MacDuff"],"question":"What is the name of Duncan's eldest son in Macbeth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rose","incorrectAnswers":["Lily","Daisy","Tulip"],"question":"What flower has cultural significance for being associated with love?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Gymnastics","Hockey","Boxing"],"question":"With which sport is Roger Bannister associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rwanda","incorrectAnswers":["United Arab Emirates","Suriname","Kazakhstan"],"question":"Kigali is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John Dillenger","incorrectAnswers":["Al Capone","Vito Corleone","Ronald Kray"],"question":"Which American gangster was shot dead outside a Chicago cinema in July 1934?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jackson Pollock","incorrectAnswers":["Raphael","René Magritte","Gustave Courbet"],"question":"Which artist painted \"No. 5, 1948\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Queensbury Rules","incorrectAnswers":["The Lonsdale Rules","The McArthur Rules","The Pugil Rules"],"question":"In Boxing, Fighting With Gloves Became Standard In 1867 After The Formulation Of Which Set Of Rules?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Alexander Graham Bell","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Edison","Guglielmo Marconi","Claude Decibel"],"question":"Who Invented The Telephone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Roman Emperor who accepted the Christian religion.","incorrectAnswers":["Holy Roman Emperor who united Germany.","Ottoman Emperor who conquered Istanbul.","French King who expelled the British from mainland Europe."],"question":"Which of the following describes Constantine the Great?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dan Brown","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Donna Leon","Frederik Pohl"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Inferno'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sapphire","incorrectAnswers":["Diamond","Gold","Silver"],"question":"In Western cultures, what is the traditional gift for a 45th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the song 'Single Ladies (Put a Ring on It)'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hyper Text Transfer Protocol","incorrectAnswers":["Hard Time Telecommunications Pact","Head To Tail Photons","High Top Transduction Paths"],"question":"In computer networking what do the initials HTTP stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lou Bega","incorrectAnswers":["Rockwell","K-Ci & JoJo","Big Country"],"question":"'Mambo No. 5 (A Little Bit Of...)' was a one hit wonder in 1999 by which artist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tiber","incorrectAnswers":["Rubicon","Romanus","Remus"],"question":"Which river runs through Rome?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ivan Turgenev","incorrectAnswers":["Leo Tolstoy","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Fathers and Sons'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Alan Shearer","incorrectAnswers":["Thierry Henry","Wayne Rooney","Robbie Fowler"],"question":"Who is the top goalscorer in the history of the English Premier League?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"David Yates","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seven","incorrectAnswers":["Two","Green","Ten"],"question":"In Italian, what is the meaning of the word 'sette'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Black Prince","incorrectAnswers":["The White Prince","The Red Prince","The Green Prince"],"question":"What was The Eldest Son Of Edward III Better Known As?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Anti-freeze","incorrectAnswers":["Brake fluid","Engine oil","Windscreen washing fluid"],"question":"For what is Ethylene glycol frequently used in automobiles?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Tempera","incorrectAnswers":["Ovoid","Mertens","Sparlas"],"question":"What is the name given to the painting medium involving egg yolks?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["The UK","Spain","China"],"question":"Which country ruled Cambodia immediately before WWII?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","United Kingdom","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders France?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An examination of the ways in which war impacts the lives of several friends.","incorrectAnswers":["An NYPD officer tries to save his wife taken hostage by terrorists during a Christmas party.","A freed slave sets out to rescue his wife from a brutal plantation-owner.","A janitor has a gift for mathematics."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Deer Hunter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Microgravity","incorrectAnswers":["Zero gravity","Minigravity","Hypergravity"],"question":"What term refers to a condition of very small gravitational forces?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Margarita","incorrectAnswers":["Bloody Mary","Mojito","Martini"],"question":"What cocktail is made with triple sec, tequila, and lime juice?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A cave","incorrectAnswers":["A museum","A cathedral","A palace"],"question":"In the South-Western French commune of Niaux, where would you find the most valuable paintings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ganges","incorrectAnswers":["Godavari","Krishna","Yamuna"],"question":"Which is the longest river in India? (not including length in other countries)","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Minnesota","incorrectAnswers":["Florida","Vermont","North Carolina"],"question":"Which of the 48 contiguous US states extends farthest north?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dravidian","incorrectAnswers":["Uralic","Koreanic","Afroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Tamil' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Spider","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Snake","Frog"],"question":"In Greek mythology, into what did Athena turn Arachne?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Apollo","incorrectAnswers":["Orion","Morpheus","Prometheus"],"question":"Who was the Greek god of prophecy and archery?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rum ","incorrectAnswers":["Vodka","Whiskey","Brandy"],"question":"Which spirit is fermented and distilled from sugar cane?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Xertz","incorrectAnswers":["Erf","Dragoman","Hullaballoo"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'to gulp down quickly and greedily'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Quattro","incorrectAnswers":["Astra","Cobra","Camry"],"question":"Which of these models of car is made by Audi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A Greyhound","incorrectAnswers":["A Bulldog","A Whippet","A Dalmatian"],"question":"Which of these is a cocktail made with gin and grapefruit juice?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"It caught fire on its launch pad","incorrectAnswers":["It landed on the moon","It was launched into the sun","It was hit by an asteroid and destroyed"],"question":"What Happened To The Apollo I Spacecraft On 27 January 1967?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Willow Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Maple Tree","Oak Tree","Birch Tree"],"question":"What type of tree is known for its 'weeping' shape?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Curtis Mayfield","incorrectAnswers":["Luther Vandross","Rick James","Bill Withers"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album 'Superfly'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Turkic","incorrectAnswers":["Japonic","Indo-European","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Kazakh' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Feeder","The Beatles","The Clash"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Another One Bites the Dust'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Colin Firth","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Penn","Billy Bob Thornton","Jean-Claude Van Damme"],"question":"Which actor has featured in both Shakespeare in Love and The English Patient?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Boston Tea Party","incorrectAnswers":["Houston Tea Party","Atlanta Tea Party","New York Tea Party"],"question":"What famous tea party took place in 1773?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Louis","incorrectAnswers":["Walter","Alexander","Donald"],"question":"What is the middle name of the Scottish author Robert Stevenson, the author of Treasure Island?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2001","incorrectAnswers":["1993","1997","2005"],"question":"In which year were the 9/11 attacks?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portugal","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Algeria","Belgium"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Spain?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gone with the Wind","incorrectAnswers":["Dark Victory","Goodbye, Mr. Chips","Love Affair"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1939?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Terry Crews","incorrectAnswers":["Richard Harris","Anthony Quinn","Hugo Weaving"],"question":"Which actor has had roles in both Brooklyn Nine-Nine and Terminator Salvation?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bracchium","incorrectAnswers":["Caput","Pedis","Oculus"],"question":"What is the Latin term for \"the arm\"?","difficulty":"hard"},